play
it's on from the opening point
well good movement from serena here at
the net
she's prepared to get involved right
from the get-go
oh what a start to this contest
drama already
in the opening couple of points
i was a little lucky off the the throat
there to get that one in then roger
really should have put that one away
[Applause]
[Music]
well that's pretty obvious that that was
a bit of a shocker
and they're there in may like the
difference casey that's what you talked
about he being francis is going to get a
lot of balls directed at him
yeah his volleys were a little bit rusty
the other night in the previous mixed
doubles but
let's hope they improve
from that one
so too
14.
[Applause]
slipped it up the middle and
opening game to america
well a good start in a sense that
we saw the doubles player on the
american team in serena get involved
quickly didn't we
yeah absolutely she was really close to
the net feet were going very explosive
looking to help tfo out when
he obviously made a good serve but yeah
lots of involvement serena which we
would expect being the doubles player
she is
okay there's a bit of a
in-house here i think about whether
roger
we'll see how it plays out
well that was a statement on that second
serve look how far inside the court
serena was
[Applause]
oh what a shot from tiapa
well that was class all around
wonderfully controlled dipping return
but look at this pick up easy that half
volley was from federer but he hugs the
middle
and what a lovely flick cross court
here today
what's interesting here in the mix we
talked about this uh the other day when
we did a mixed together case is that
sometimes in the mix it's easier for the
woman if the man hits it hard and flat
on serve
whereas roger is just really using the
cat spin isn't he
yeah
i always feel that pace and for someone
like serena pace isn't a problem it's
the movement of the ball it's the kick
it's a slice it's into the body those
are the ones that trouble players and
especially female players because we
just don't see that type of movement on
the ball the hard and fast ones can
potentially sometimes be a little bit
easier to handle
plenty of anticipation for this serve
fifteen
[Applause]
[Music]
christmases
thank you
well average forehand topspin speeds
today
just 1k less for serena
oh she was out after that one
even roger turn to look at the clock
[Applause]
well that was a
very very good second serve
that was better than good i think yeah
[Applause]
well it's a challenge
it's a bit of a late one
but it's uh going to get reviewed
two of the greatest spot servers the
game's ever seen
both finding their spots hitting them
with
unnerving accuracy
good start by the american
team and now this is a crucial game
about to come on the serve of belinda
bentich
[Music]
someone's already a winner
[Applause]
the pendulum of pressure swings to the
swiss team with benchit serving
okay so i'm not sure how you felt when
you're playing mixture when you're
serving but as the male when i was on
court i was thought always thought it
was crucial that my partner the female
made of first server didn't matter the
pace to me so much it was just the
pressure i could help more on a first
serve than i could on the second and so
it's crucial here for linda
[Music]
just like that there to get a free point
every now and then and let roger be seen
it's exactly the one thing as the female
that you need to make a priority when
you are playing mixed doubles is like
you said not necessarily big first
serves just good placement and get your
male counterpart involved at the net
roger trying to make himself as low as
possible there so that he knew benchitch
wanted to find the angle
[Applause]
uh
[Music]
you watch serena here she doesn't watch
the path of the ball she keeps her eyes
stuck forward in court so she had no
idea where that ball was going so
couldn't actually flow with the doubles
point where she watched roger he he
looks behind and watches the flow of the
balls a little bit more instinctive
because of that
fourteen
[Applause]
yeah that must feel good when you get a
little
pat on the back from
roger i thought here
she could potentially
could have even gone down through the
middle a bit more
or potentially at serena's feet a little
bit more but
reflexes were spot-on
played a great next volley
electrifying
15.
it's interesting isn't it in a way
because you can see the
team switzer paying respect to serena by
targeting the volleying of trfo
[Applause]
nearly put a dent in serena's ambitions
for australia i think
[Applause]
well these things are all about timing
watch roger he takes a little side step
he reads where the racket head is of
tiarfo he's off early so much so that he
gets that one on the forehand but it's
the way he moves forward to cover the
net that is the important part
15.
[Applause]
she takes a little jump to a right
educated guess look at this
15 14.
two break points
switzerland
forehand there from tiapo and
switzerland get the upper hand
better after the sit-down will serve for
the opening set switzerland leads three
games to two
so the americans have got to fashion up
a break a serve here otherwise this
opening set in this fast four format
will get away from them
[Applause]
deceptively quick at times isn't it you
can't really read that it's going to
come through as fast as that
well i think he you know through through
that hit zone sometimes he hits it
flatter other times he spins it more and
it's very hard to pick that up
you know at that last moment as he
accelerates through contact
[Applause]
it's another above 100 mile an hour
second serve from federer
giving serena's returns the respect that
they're due
but he's coming out on top of the moment
as our switzerland with three set points
[Music]
[Applause]
once again coming to the party
effectively
well that set played out probably how we
thought it might in a way i mean roger
to the back end started to dominate a
little bit but francis
yeah the fella can't lose sir
it's the ultimate sin of mixed doubles
casey yeah we spoke about it didn't we
talk about
how important holding the female serve
is but in this case francis obviously
lost his serve which clearly is why they
lost this first set but really compose
good composed tennis from belinda
particularly she just made a little bit
of a difference there in the end with
that return
across her body which won them that game
and then even in this last game just
being
composed enough to take volleys on and
she is a really solid
uh mixed doubles player out there
when you watch roger like that you
wonder you know had he decided to play a
lot more doubles at major level how many
he would have won i played in the era as
you did uh mark with pete sampras
different league in terms i played a lot
pete was a chipper of returns didn't
have the quality of returning that roger
possesses and
but this man it just would have been
endless wouldn't it i would have put my
hand up to play with him
everyone i mean it you you look at how
sparingly he plays doubles and how good
he is and how instinctive he is at the
movement of the net to cover the middle
and keep going you look at him at the
labour cup i mean you know
it's phenomenal that he's lost none of
his ability to see the options and the
angles out there on a doubles court as
well
[Music]
usa up against it here down a set to
switzerland in the deciding mixed
doubles
oh
well you can't quite take the full line
up the line there casey got to ask you
is there an argument here that serena
should have served first well i was just
about to bring that up and wanted to see
what your thoughts were but if it was
me
i would have almost preferred to see
serena serving first
three of us agree
oh
a couple reasons i've done both of
francis's match his first percentage has
not been great
and puts a lot of pressure on this one
coming
but also
serena as we mentioned has such a good
first serve you know it's the best serve
in women's tennis it's equal to many of
the men serves on tour and that's when
the fella at net can do his work it's
it's really easy for for francis to get
in there and just you know knock off a
few simple volleys yeah and i also felt
at the end of serena's singles match she
really found rhythm on her serve
so i would go with that
makes a difference if you get the first
one in though
okay
[Applause]
[Music]
well that was a bit loose from blender
she had plenty of time to
keep that one in and pepper
right location todd yeah there's nothing
wrong with the middle especially if
people haven't played together much
before
[Applause]
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
right
on the chest
sorry buddy
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
not sure whether that was because that
was so heavy and so much spin and it
propped or
tommy just out all together for tiafoe
30-15
fourteen
[Applause]
[Music]
such great push from his legs federer
you look at the lift he gets up off the
court from that platform stance
that's what they almost look like okay
do i rip it at serena
and then there was a hesitation and
changed his mind and went to take it
back through the center i think i think
for me that was where that error came
from
oh
15.
serena there looking like she was just
hanging on to her right shoulder a
little bit
i've contest with benchitch earlier
she wasn't hanging under anything on
that serve just a little long but 192
kilometers an hour
well that's what the crowd came to see
didn't they
a beautiful cross court rally there from
serena
against roger roger back to serena
roger not making any headway against
serena so decided i hit it at the net
player and
got his reward
turtle
can you see roger talking to belinda
he's coaching her through it isn't he
coaching in a way of like okay this is
what we're going to do there's a real
strategy planned to the coaching
and they did it on change of ends
belinda moved over to sit closer to
roger and they spoke through the whole
change of ends
it's essential in any good doubles
combination to be able to talk and
communicate
oh just a bit too big on the swing in
the volley
i used to
communicate a lot with my partners so
much so that they used to turn off and
not listen anymore but they knew that it
was good for me to get it out
for service
oh
a couple of misses from benches say that
she'll be a little bit disappointed by
it
and the americans survived
bit of pressure on their serve
a big service game coming up here for
melinda benticic
well i'd like to see serena get a second
serve here and just hammer it down
rogers line really take him on
oh
he's got him
the tournament director nelly died of a
heart attack not not just the one here
in perth no the one in melbourne yeah tv
executives and everyone
i'll tell you what
the payback was swift
fortunately that was just a glance on
the side of the head if it got an eye or
something else
and that's your turn
i think it was serena saying happy new
year
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
still holding onto his ear there it's
spinning uh double the size right now
you gotta expect to be hitting doubles
yeah just a little bit of pressure here
now on belinda
in this game
[Applause]
thank you
no that all comes from
roger
moving at net and being so involved
because the returner starts to take
their eye off the ball and you get a bit
early or you can be a bit late whichever
it may be but it becomes because you
look up
too early
took a little step on telfo's uh service
game serena certainly did it there
didn't she she almost said to not only
move but she almost had a racket back
just waiting for her
great point for the americans
use
this
he narrows the court so well doesn't he
fed her at the net with his movement
there and tiafa was trying to thread it
past him but he had his eyes todd was
saying off the ball of course this is a
deciding point here
lady to lady or men to men if they were
serving so uh bench itch to serena
williams
nice
that might have been like match point
right
there well that was a very very
critical point in regards to the outcome
of this match absolutely what a response
bench it's rising to the occasion there
was a bit of pressure on the it was the
loosest that she's played so far in the
mixed doubles in the last couple of
games but uh she's rescued the situation
i think federer was pretty happy with
that
that one as well
oh
well he's been waiting for his
opportunity casey to do it
yeah right time and it is a good play
to go directly obviously i
serena's racket's out in front she's
ready for it but
it's still a very difficult shot to play
15-00
[Applause]
not a million miles away
well there's just a few points in the
last couple of games that have become
very important that
linda has just either missed or made the
wrong decision or just a step too slow
but every point you can feel in this
fast four short sets format
is becoming very crucial
[Applause]
just too much wrist action in there from
serena
so much pace on the ball she just needed
to put string on it guide it
40 50.
[Applause]
well
i actually can't believe she's missed
that
deciding point
[Applause]
three miss volleys in this game from
serena
and
it's the americans under pressure on
their serve this time
[Music]
they survive
and swiss
usa a bit of work to do in this second
set still
oh
they're serving to take it into the
tiebreaker
oh
[Applause]
um
[Music]
again there you can see just a
little bit of stiffness in that right
shoulder
and a bit of tightness on the scoreboard
[Applause]
first of five points there'll be two
serves coming up here from serena
williams
followed by two from belinda bentich and
so forth
we get two uh three apiece then and the
next two points are split there'll be a
third
service point by the current server at
that stage
good play
yeah almost the best movement from tiapo
we've seen throughout the match zero
usa just see he was expecting this one
to come to him but then
to be prepared to move for the next one
roger just explaining the rules to
to everyone
good shot
saw the space open out a bit of damage
limitation
attempted there by federer
such as the fear of feather across him
that serena was trying to take him out
of the picture by hitting it up high
yes that was
that result the unforced error was a
result of federer's movement there at
the net
and again belinda just so solid from her
corner
and roger helping her out there at the
net creating an error from the racket of
tfo
so
both teams just stopping for a brief pit
stop there as they change ends
it's a single session record here at the
uh mastercard hotman cup as you can see
at the bottom right there 14 064 fans
crammed into the rac perth
arena
and i don't think one person has left
their seat
for this mixed doubles match have they
three
two usa
serena this time with a good move
what i said
wow
not a great serve it seemed like a great
surf
in the end it was a fantastic hawkeye
challenge
one millimeter
good young eyes from
federer belinda ever stop moving he is
perpetual motion isn't he
and it is very much advantage
the swiss now because roger federer has
three service points to come
[Applause]
[Music]
four
three
switzerland
match point for the swiss to get the
victory over the americans
it's done in such style
well they have you both on the same
court at the same time in a live match
like that is something special not just
for everybody in the house but for
everybody around the world serena what
was that experience like for you
well it was a great experience i'm kind
of sad it's over you know i was just
warming up
hey i'm sure the folks here will let us
come back out and play some more
[Applause]
no it was it was so fun and i you know
this is like i said before it's
something that as growing up and and
what as we grew up together really just
watching and having an opportunity after
all these years we've actually never
done this so this is super cool that we
get to do it at such a pinnacle point in
both our careers and for me it was super
cool like i've literally like wanted to
take pictures and i
want to bring my baby out i'm like way
too excited
but it was it was really fun roger what
stood out for you about coming up
against serena uh in her game
well i was nervous returning because
because you just don't know but people
talk about her surf so much and i see
why it is such a wonderful serve because
you just can't read it you don't see
until they're very jars either well
we have the same qualities you know but
yours is a bit better but uh no it's
true but anyway
for me it was a bit nerve-wracking too
to be honest because all of a sudden
you're serving especially the last serve
at three all i'm like i gotta win this
point but it's serena williams i was
telling myself and i was telling myself
this is maybe what i've always wanted
maybe
a big time moment like this and i made
the serve but i actually totally missed
the target and thank you for missing the
ball but uh it was a it was a great
great great fun and um yeah great
champion you see how focused and
determined she is and i love that about
her and then what
and for you serena
to answer that same question to come out
against roger you've watched a lot of
his play what stood out against playing
the ball that he delivers
well i mean the guy is great i mean he's
the greatest of all time to be honest
and
[Music]
both on the court and off the court and
he has such charisma he's just wonderful
player um
i think
um i mean i'm trying to narrow it down
here but
you know and i don't know if this is the
right thing to say i think his serve is
super underestimated he has a killer
serve like literally you can't read it
like i said you can't read it and
there's a reason why he's the greatest
because you can't be that great not have
such an awesome weapon like that serve
so i was really i watched them all the
time but i never knew how amazing it was
so it was it was really cool to kind of
learn hopefully i can get some tips
later on on how to how to get to get a
little better but it was really
impressive i think if you two start
giving tips well the rest of the feel
and the australian open maze will go
home
now listen um you did speak to me the
other day and said that you wanted to
have a selfie
with roger and you haven't had that
photo so we've got one of our yeah it's
going to happen
here we go
ryder you're in control is it is it on
we kind of need our rackets
would you like to go get your rackets
i'll wait here with the selfie stick
while you two go and get your rackets
in tv land folks they call this padding
while the talent leaves you
okay here we go you guys are in control
who's going to do that ladies and
gentlemen why these two champions take
in this moment for themselves would you
put your hands together one more time
for serena williams and roger federer
oh
[Applause]
you